hello friends lot of people are having
this query whether my health insurance
or medical empowers coronavirus or not
let us understand in detail about it if
you look at the policy workings of any
health insurance it clearly states that
viruses will be covered as a part of
medically coronavirus being the virus
will be covered under your medical aim
so you need not worry if you have an
existing policy now another question is
after what amount will I be covered you
will be covered for the entire sum
assured for example you have an engineer
C or group only see with the sum assured
of rupees 5 lakhs so you can use the
entire sum assured of rupees 5 lakhs for
Khurana subject to the specific
conditions in your health policy there
won't be any capping or coronavirus now
what if tomorrow
Karuna gets declared as an act of water
say if we come to know that china had
used it as a bio weapon to take down the
world then in that circumstance it will
be considered as an act of war and all
insurance policies specifically exclude
cases which are a result of water and
thus use of biological weapon would
exclude you from getting yourself
covered under health insurance so next
question is what if I take a new medical
policy today will I be eligible to claim
coronavirus treatment expenses answer is
yes but there will be a cooling period
of 30 days for example if you buy a
policy today you won't be eligible to
take the claim for first 30 days post
that you would be eligible to claim
benefit under health insurance the next
question which arises is what on
specific items will be covered if I get
admitted all items such as room brain
charges consultancy fees agnostic
charges many sins etc will be covered
however aya DA has given a list of
standard non payable items like
consumables so what do you mean by
consumables mask
Klauss PPE kit which is used by doctors
and nurses won't be covered under your
medical policy so what needs to be
really careful that hospitals don't
charge you exorbitant lehigh amount for
such consumables as they have to be made
from your own pocket
another question is will I be able to
get the cashless facility if I visit the
network Hospital answer is yes but only
if PP is functional so what do you mean
by PPA PPA is a third party
administrator who looks after your claim
settlements however if TB is not
functional you may have to pay in cash
first and then claim for reimbursement
here we come to the end of presentation
hope you liked it stay home stay safe to
know more about investment personal
finance and insurance kinda like a
Instagram channel or follow us on
YouTube thank you